Corn currently accounts for more than
one tenth of our global crop /krɒp/ production /prəˈdʌkʃən/.
The United States alone has enough
cornfields to cover Germany.
But while other crops we grow
come in a range of varieties /vəˈraɪətɪ/,
over 99% of cultivated corn is the
exact /ɪɡˈzækt/ same type: Yellow Dent #2.
This means that humans grow
more Yellow Dent #2
than any other plant on the planet.
So how did this single variety
of this single plant
become the biggest success story
in agricultural history?
Nearly 9,000 years ago, corn,
also called maize /meɪz 玉米；黄色/,
was first domesticated /dəˈmestɪkeɪt 驯养；驯化 培育；使归化/ from teosinte /ˌtiːəʊˈsɪntɪ  墨西哥类蜀黍/,
a grass native to Mesoamerica /ˌmesəʊəˈmerɪkə 中美洲/.
Teosinte’s rock-hard seeds
were barely /ˈbɛəlɪ/ edible /ˈɛdəbəl/,
but its fibrous /ˈfaɪbrəs 纤维的/ husk /hʌsk 外壳，外皮/ could be turned
into a versatile /ˈvɜːsəˌtaɪl 多才多艺的；多用途的/ material , like sleeping mats /mæt 席子；垫子/
Over the next 4,700 years, farmers bred /breed的过去/
the plant into a staple /ˈsteɪpəl 主要的/ crop,
with larger cobs /kɒb 玉米棒子/ and edible kernels /ˈkɜːnəl/.
As maize spread throughout the Americas,
it took on an important role,
with multiple indigenous /ɪnˈdɪdʒɪnəs 土生土长的/ societies
revering /rɪˈvɪə 尊敬；崇敬/ a “Corn Mother”
as the goddess who created agriculture.
When Europeans first arrived in America,
they shunned /ʃʌn 避开，避免；回避/ the strange plant.
Many even believed it was the source of
physical and cultural differences
between them and the Mesoamericans.
However,
their attempts to cultivate European crops
in American soil quickly failed,
and the settlers were forced
to expand their diet /ˈdaɪət/.
Finding the crop to their taste,
maize soon crossed the Atlantic,
where its ability to grow in diverse
climates made it a popular grain
in many European countries.
But the newly established United States
was still the corn capital of the world.
In the early 1800’s, different regions
across the country
produced strains /streɪn 品种 压力/ of varying /ˈvɛərɪ 改变；变化；使多样化/
size and taste.
In the 1850’s, however,
these unique /juːˈniːk/ varieties /vəˈraɪətɪ/ proved /pruːvd 证实/ difficult
for train operators to package,
and for traders to sell.
Trade boards in rail hubs like Chicago
encouraged corn farmers
to breed one standardized crop.
This dream would finally be
realized at 1893’s World’s Fair,
where James Reid’s yellow dent corn
won the Blue Ribbon.
Over the next 50 years, yellow dent
corn swept the nation.
Following the technological
developments of World War II,
mechanized /mekənaiz  使机械化/ harvesters became
widely available.
This meant a batch of corn that previously /ˈpriːvɪəslɪ 以前/
took a full day to harvest by hand
could now be collected in just 5 minutes.
Another wartime technology, the chemical
explosive ammonium /əˈməʊnɪəm 氨盐基,铵/ nitrate /ˈnaɪtreɪt 硝酸盐;硝酸钾;硝酸钠/,
also found new life on the farm.
With this new synthetic /sɪnˈθɛtɪk 合成的，人造的/ fertilizer,
farmers could plant dense /dens 稠密的/ fields
of corn year after year,
without the need to rotate /rəʊˈteɪt/ their crops
and restore nitrogen /ˈnaɪtrədʒən 氮/ to the soil.
While these advances made corn an
attractive crop to American farmers,
US agricultural policy limited the
amount farmers could grow
to ensure high sale prices.
But in 1972, President Richard Nixon /ˈnɪksən/
removed these limitations
while negotiating massive grain  /ɡreɪn 谷物/
sales to the Soviet /ˈsəʊvɪət/ Union.
With this new trade deal
and WWII technology,
corn production exploded /ɪkˈspləʊd 爆炸/ into
a global phenomenon.
These mountains of maize inspired /ɪnˈspaɪəd 鼓舞 灵感/
numerous corn concoctions /kənˈkɒkʃən 调制品；调制/.
Cornstarch could be used as a thickening  /thickening agent 增稠剂/
agent for everything from gasoline to glue /ɡluː 胶水/
or processed into a low-cost sweetener /ˈswiːtənə 甜味剂/
known as High-Fructose /ˈfrʊktəʊz 果糖/ Corn Syrup /ˈsɪrəp 糖浆/.
Maize quickly became one of the
cheapest animal feeds /fiːd 饲料/ worldwide.
This allowed for inexpensive
meat production,
which in turn increased the demand
for meat and corn feed.
Today, humans eat only 40% of
all cultivated corn,
while the remaining 60% supports consumer
good industries worldwide.
Yet the spread of this wonder/ˈwʌndə 惊奇/-crop
has come at a price.
Global water sources are polluted by
excess ammonium /əˈməʊnɪəm 氨盐基,铵/ nitrate /ˈnaɪtreɪt 硝酸盐/ from cornfields.
Corn accounts for a large portion of
agriculture-related carbon emissions,
partly due to the increased meat
production it enables.
The use of high fructose /ˈfrʌkˌtoʊs 果糖/ corn syrup /ˈsɪrəp 糖浆/ may
be a contributor to diabetes /ˌdaɪəˈbiːtɪs  糖尿病/ and obesity /əuˈbi:siti 肥胖/.
And the rise of monoculture /ˈmɒnəʊˌkʌltʃə 单一栽培/ farming
has left our food supply dangerously
vulnerable to pests and pathogens /ˈpæθəˌdʒɛn 病原体/—
a single virus could infect the world’s
supply of this ubiquitous /juːˈbɪkwɪtəs 无所不在的/ crop.
Corn has gone from a bushy grass
to an essential element of the
world’s industries.
But only time will tell if it has led us
into a maze /meɪz 迷宫/ of unsustainability.